

# SIPHOSETHU NYAWO

#### **BUSINESS ANALYST**

Address:

81 Gillespie St, South Beach, Durban, 4001 (Willing to relocate)

Phone:

0764609833 /0723793552

**Email address:** 

Funluckysipho@gmail.com

# **EDUCATION**

**Higher institution:** Durban University of Technology

**Education Qualification:** 

Diploma in Information and Communications Technology in Business

Analysis (ICT). **Year:** 2020-2022

High School Name: Msiyane High School

Education Qualification: Matric

Certificate **Year:** 2019

#### **SKILLS**

- Ability to quickly learn new tasks.
- Ability to work under pressure.
- Excel data sources
- Agile business analysis
- Analytical thinking and problem solving
- Collaborating skills
- Being detailed-oriented and capable of delivering a high level of accuracy

## **HOBBIES**

- Gym
- Reading books and socializing with people
- Travelling and exploring the world
- Listening to music

## **PROFILE**

I am an energetic, confident, and dedicated business analyst with experience in requirements gathering, documentation, and preparing professional presentations. I have 1 year of experience obtained in the higher education sector; I was working directly with the database analyst in the department of data analytics and data sciences. I have a good idea of new activities and ways of encouraging groups, and I do my best on individual tasks.

Availability: Immediately

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Position**: Intern

**Department**: Data Analytics and Data Sciences

Company: Durban University of Technology (DUT)

Year: From 2023-03-01 to 2024-02-29

- Collecting data from disparate systems into one Higher Education Data Analyzer software (PowerHEDA).
- Extracting data from the SQL Server.
- Extracting data from the ITS integrator.
- Writing SQL queries for production data extraction.
- Creating MS queries to extract data into Excel.
- Creating reports using a Microsoft Power Automate and SQL database.
- Preparing and presenting comprehensive reports to stakeholders, effectively communicating complex data findings in a clear and concise manner.
- Collaborating with IT teams to enhance data infrastructure, systems, and tools to support data analysis and reporting.
- Performing quantitative and qualitative analysis to assist senior leaders in evaluating possible solutions to solve complex organizational problems.
- Working directly with the database analyst to achieve the best actions to take.
- Data modeling and programming using HTML, C#, Python, and Visio.

## **REFERENCES**

Name : Prabashnee Kisten

Position : Snr Information Analyst Email : kistenp@dut.ac.za

**Contact No.** : 083 453 3214 & 031 373 5128

Name:Mbongiseni NdlovuPosition:Database AnalystEmail:wisemann@dut.ac.za

**Contact No.** : 073 164 3079 & 031 373 5488

Name:Thaveshnee NaidoPosition:Information AnalystEmail:naidoo\_c@dut.ac.za

**Contact No.** : 073 121 6210 & 031 373 6834

**Statement:** I solemnly declare that the information rendered above is correct in every respect.

Regards, Mr. SZB Nyawo